john.fragkoulis@gmail.com

You can visit my website to read more about my working experience and projects @ jfragoulis.github.io

Nea Ionia, Athens, Greece

15/09/1984 No military obligations

I engaged in programming when I was 16 years old and have been passionate about the craft since then. The original stimulus came from computer games and the need to learn how to develop them myself. I began by learning c++ and windows programming. I am a person who always seeks for new things to learn and new technologies to use whenever given the chance. Over the years I have studied artificial intelligence, physics and graphics and have worked as a web developer and tools programmer. I am also an avid open source supporter and linux user and I try to give back to the community as much as possible.

EMPLOYMENT

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Durration: 04/2015 - current

Location: Athens, Greece

http://www.skroutz.gr Skroutz

As a member of the Platform team and as Internal Tools Lead, I take part in the development of several in-house projects and services.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Durration: 02/2012 - 04/2015

Location: Athens, Greece

http://www.ekt.gr National Documentation Centre

Research and development from ground up of National Documentation Center's new Integrated Library System with Yii/PHP and the latest of web technologies principles.

WEB DEVELOPER

Duration: 02/2011 - 12/2011

Location: Athens, Greece

http://youtu.be/P9MtPqrjoog?hd=1 MSLeague

Development of an ambitious online fantasy football game with Yii/PHP (full-stack).

INFRASTRUCTURE PROGRAMMER

Duration: 09/2008 - 10/2009

Location: Horsham, UK

http://www.creative-assembly.co.uk

The Creative Assembly

Developed and maintained asset management tools for **Total War: Empire** and **Total War: Napoleon.** Worked on file and memory management for Windows XP. Maintained and expanded the virtual file and patching system written in C++.

WEB DEVELOPER

Duration: 05/2006 - 08/2007

Location: Athens, Greece

http://www.sentel.co

Sentel Technologies and Consulting

Developed dozens of small and large websites such as money-market.gr, ypotrofies.gr, keat.gr. In the process I developed an in-house content management system in PHP that supported multilingual content and had a fully featured user management system. (full-stack)

EDUCATION

- Sep. '07 Sep. '08: University of Hull, UK, Masters in Games Programming, Grade: 71/100 (with distinction)

 <u>Dissertation:</u> "Games that learn about their users and adapt", a promising look on how adaptive and learning AI can be applied to games
- Sep. '02 July '07: University of Piraeus, Greece, Ptychion in Informatics, Grade: 7.2/10

LANGUAGES

- Fluent: PHP, Javascript, SQL, Ruby
- Conversational: C++
- Exposed: Ruby, Java, GLSL, C#, Python, ActionScript, Prolog, Bourne Shell, Pascal, MIPS assembly, Matlab,
 VRML, HLSL

SKILLS

- Object-Oriented design skills
- Experienced with frameworks and libraries like Ruby on Rails, Yii, jQuery, Knockout, Boost, STL
- Experienced in source code revision tools (Git, Perforce, Subversion)
- Experienced with Visual Studio and Netbeans
- Admin level knowledge: Unix/Linux operating systems, Windows XP/Vista/7
- Able to comfortably find my way through the insides of PC hardware

REFERENCES

Available on request